Rein...
Rein ...
You're fired.
Kamu dipecat.
(Meeting of Fate)
(Pertemuan Takdir)
Beast Tamer.
Beast Tamer.
It's a class that is able to communicate
Bisa berkomunikasi dan membuat kontrak ...
and enter into contracts with many kinds of animals...
... dengan bermacam hewan.
Taming their strength as your own.
Kelas yang memakai kekuatan hewan.
Beast Tamers aren't well-suited to combat,
Beast Tamer tak cocok untuk bertarung.
but I worked hard to support my comrades during our harsh journey,
Tapi sebagai anggota party pahlawan,
Or... so I thought.
Kukira begitu.
Um, hang on a sec.
Eh, tunggu sebentar.
This is kind of sudden, so I'm not sure I follow...
Aku bingung, ini terlalu mendadak ...
Wait, is this a prank?
Ah, ini gurauan, ya?
Of course not.
Tentu saja tidak.
Arios...
Arios ...
Aggath?
Aggath?
Leane?
Leane?
Mina?
Mina?
You're... serious about this?
Serius ... nih?
I-I want to know why!
Ka-Katakan alasannya!
You want a reason?
Alasannya?
You mean other than the obvious one?
Jelas cuma satu, 'kan?
It's because you're useless!
Kamu tuh beban!
You don't serve any purpose!
Kamu tidak berguna!
Do you get it now?
Mengerti?
You've been holding us back so much,
Kamu membebani kami dan malah merugikan kami.
I am...?
Merugikan?
You have to have noticed, right?
Kamu menyadarinya, 'kan?
You never do any damage to our enemies,
Kamu tak pernah melukai musuh ...
and we're constantly having to save you.
... dan malah merepotkan kami.
All you really contribute is scouting and carriage,
Bisamu cuma memakai hewan ...
using the animals that you've tamed.
... untuk mengintai dan membawa barang.
Doesn't that sound worthless to you?
Kalau bukan tak berguna, harus disebut apa, tuh?
It was asking too much of him in the first place.
Percuma membahas ini.
What is this...?
Apa-apaan ini ...?
We don't have time for babysitting.
Ngajak anak kecil tuh merepotkan.
I was always against letting a Beast Tamer join up.
Lagian aku menentang Beast Tamer bergabung.
Don't be like that.
Jangan bilang begitu.
Worthless as he is, I thought he could shine by sharing the same spotlight as me.
Kukira kerikil sepertinya bisa bersinar karena pengaruhku.
Arios, you are so kind!
Arios, kamu baik banget!
Very. The only sin here lies with this man
Ya, dialah yang berdosa ...
who has wasted the grace of the Hero, Arios.
... karena menyia-nyiakan kebaikan pahlawan Arios.
This is what my party thought of me this whole time?
Teman-temanku selama ini ...
I... This can't—
Tidak. Aku—
Rein...
Rein ...
Don't lower our opinion of you any more than you already have.
Jangan kecewakan kami lagi.
And make sure to leave your gear behind.
Oh, tinggalkan perlengkapanmu.
We're the ones who gathered it.
Kami yang mengumpulkannya.
This means we can finally take on the Lost Woods.
Kita akhirnya bisa menaklukkan Hutan Sesat.
We've waited long enough.
Iya, akhirnya.
I understand.
Baiklah.
This town is big, but there's nothing in it, and we've been here for days.
Tertahan berhari-hari di kota besar kosong ini ...
How long was he going to spend on gathering supplies, anyway?
Si beban lama banget ngumpulin persediaan.
We were mistaken to have even the most modest hopes for him.
Kita salah sudah mengharapkannya.
Let us simply consider this a brief respite.
Anggap saja liburan singkat.
Good idea!
Bagus, tuh!
When you put of it that way, maybe he was of some use at the very end.
Jika berpikir begitu, si beban bisa agak guna.
In that moment...
Saat itu ...
It felt like anything between us had come to a permanent end.
... ikatan kami rasanya benar-benar terputus.
You're weak, like a child.
Kau cuma anak lemah, ya.
You still seem to lack both the bearing and the skill required of the Hero's party.
Sebagai anggota party pahlawan ...
Are you ever going to be good for anything besides running errands?
Kapan kamu bisa guna selain jadi suruhan?
So worthless...
Nggak guna banget.
No need to be so harsh. Rein is trying his best.
Jangan bilang begitu.
At least, for a Beast Tamer!
... tapi cuma sebagai Beast Tamer!
I thought the reason they were so hard on me
Mereka keras padaku saat perjalanan ...
was because they had high hopes for what I could accomplish.
... kukira karena mereka mengandalkanku.
But...
Tapi ...
Maybe they never cared about me in the first place.
Mereka tak melihatku sebagai teman sejak awal.
But more importantly, what do I do now?
Yah, sekarang enaknya gimana, ya?
No goal, no gear, and no coin.
Tujuan, peralatan, dan koin ...
I'm starting with next to nothing.
Semuanya telah hilang.
Rein!
Kak Rein!
Did you finish your job for the Hero?
Kelar bantu pahlawan?
Uh, actually...
Yah, aku ...
Do the thing then, come on!
Lakukan yang biasanya!
Please!
Lakukan!
Come on, please!
Ayo lakukan!
Do it! Go on!
Lakukan, dong!
Okay!
Oke!
So, for today...
Untuk hari ini ...
There.
Sip.
That's the temporary contract.
Kontrak sementara selesai.
Go on, say hello.
Oke, beri salam.
Wow!
Hebat!
Nice job.
Kerja bagus.
And thank you.
Terima kasih.
Bye-bye!
Bye-bye!
See you around!
Sampai jumpa!
There it goes...
Sudah pergi, tuh ...
Well, like I told you, that contract was only temporary.
Aku pernah bilang, ini kontrak sementara, sih.
They're easy to form, but they don't last very long.
Ini mudah dibentuk, tapi cuma sebentar.
Maybe that was a little hard to understand?
Kalian sulit memahaminya, ya?
You really are awesome, Rein!
Kak Rein memang hebat!
I wanna be a Beast Tamer when I grow up!
Aku kelak akan menjadi Beast Tamer!
Me, too!
Aku juga!
Huh...
Eh ...
I thought you said you wanted to be a hero before?
Kemarin bilangnya jadi pahlawan, 'kan?
I mean, the Hero and his party always look annoyed
Saat jelata seperti kami mendekati party pahlawan ...
when commoners like us come up to them!
... mereka terlihat sangat kesal!
Even though they suck up to rich folks and nobles...
Beda kalau didekati bangsawan atau orang kaya.
It's kind of nasty, right?
Bikin jijik, 'kan?
And scary.
Seram.
I didn't know people thought that way about Arios and the party.
Reputasi party Arios seburuk ini, ya.
I guess that explains the reception I got whenever I went to buy supplies.
Wajar setiap toko ogah-ogahan saat aku ngisi persediaan.
You're different though, Rein!
Tapi Kak Rein berbeda!
You always play with us!
Ya, kakak selalu main sama kami!
And you're nice!
Dan juga baik!
It's gonna be even harder to tell them I got fired now.
Makin sulit buat bilang soal dipecat.
So I'm gonna be an adventurer, and travel all over!
Aku akan jadi petualang dan pergi ke banyak tempat!
And make a fortune overnight!
Dan kaya mendadak!
A fortune!
Kaya!
A fortune overnight! A fortune overnight!
Kaya mendadak!
An adventurer...
Petualang ...
Living like a migratory bird on the wing, free to live or die as I please.
Bebas hidup dan mati seperti burung yang bermigrasi.
Making a living off my skills by taking jobs as an adventurer?
Cari uang dari keahlianku ...
Now that I don't need to worry about defeating the Demon King,
Aku tak lagi bertujuan mengalahkan Raja Iblis ...
it might be the perfect job for me.
... itu mungkin cocok buatku.
Okay!
Oke!
Welcome to the Adventurer's Guild!
Selamat datang di Guild Petualang!
I'm Natalie, the receptionist.
Saya resepsionis Natalie.
Let's start with an explanation of the adventurer's trial.
Saya akan jelaskan tentang tes petualang.
Could you tell me a bit more about being an adventurer first?
Oh, bisa jelaskan soal petualang dulu?
I hate to admit it, but I actually don't know that much.
Malu mengakuinya, tapi aku tak begitu tahu.
Arios and the others looked down on adventurers,
Arios dan yang lain merendahkan petualang ...
so we didn't interact with them much.
... jadi jarang ada interaksi.
You're an earnest one, aren't you?
Kamu orangnya serius, ya.
Most of the applicants don't really put too much thought into it...
Banyak pelamar yang mengabaikannya ...
Personally, I think you're on the right track!
Bagiku, kamu punya nilai tinggi!
You really do?
Benarkah?
I really do!
Iya!
Let's start at the beginning, then.
Saya mulai jelaskan, ya.
Adventurers, like monsters, are assigned ranks from S to F...
Petualang, seperti monster, punya Rank dari S sampai F ...
...and that's everything.
... sekian.
Is there anything else you had questions about?
Ada pertanyaan lain?
Nope. Thank you.
Tidak. Terima kasih.
I should be good, now.
Sudah cukup.
In that case, let's move onto the matter of the adventurer's trial.
Nah, selanjutnya tentang tes petualang.
What's your class?
Apa kelasmu?
Beast Tamer.
Beast Tamer.
Beast Tamer?!
Beast Tamer?!
Um... will you be okay by yourself?
Um ... kamu yakin sendiri?
It's because you're useless!
Kamu tuh beban!
Don't do anything reckless, okay?
Jangan memaksakan diri, ya?
Adventurers need to know when a job is too much.
Petualang harus tahu kapan harus menyerah.
Right. Of course.
Ya. Tentu saja.
Do you understand why the guild requires a trial
Kamu tahu kenapa guild melakukan tes ...
in order to be registered as an adventurer?
... untuk calon petualang?
Is it because if there were a bunch of unskilled adventurers,
Karena jika petualang terus gagal dalam misi ...
it'd undermine trust in the guild?
... guild akan kurang dipercaya?
Correct! Well done!
Tepat! Bagus!
And without that trust, the government would get involved.
Jika kurang dipercaya, pemerintah akan terlibat.
But putting that aside, the details of the trial involve slaying ten goblins,
Yah, kesampingkan itu.
and collecting 20 medicinal herbs.
... dan mengumpulkan 20 herba.
Adventurers take on a variety hunting and collection jobs,
Misi petualang ...
so this is the bare minimum required to pass muster with the guild.
Minimal harus bisa itu agar guild mengakuimu.
That's ten.
Ini sepuluh.
Thanks for helping me find the goblins.
Terima kasih sudah bantu nyari goblin.
I guess even a Beast Tamer can handle F-ranked monsters like them.
Yah, Beast Tamer pun bisa mudah menangani goblin Rank F.
I've got the rune stones from the goblins,
Batu sihir goblin didapatkan.
so I just need to gather the herbs and head back to the guild...
Setelah ngumpulin herba, bawa ke guild ...
A scream?
Teriakan?
It's from further in the forest!
Dari dalam hutan?
A Killer Tiger?!
Killer Tiger?!
Oh, no!
Gawat!
The D-Ranked monster Killer Tiger.
Monster Rank D, Killer Tiger.
Even a veteran adventurer could be killed by one of these if they weren't careful!
Bahkan petualang veteran bisa terbunuh jika ceroboh!
And of course, I don't stand a chance.
Aku jelas tak bisa menandinginya.
But...
Tapi ...
It's better this way.
Mending begini.
Hey, you!
Hei, kamu!
Can you move?
Bisa gerak?
You need to run while you can!
Larilah sekarang!
No monsters to tame.
Tak ada hewan untuk dijinakkan.
No weapons to use.
Dan tak ada senjata.
But I can at least buy her enough time to get away...
Tapi setidaknya,
Wh-Why are you still there?!
Wah, kok masih di situ?!
With the last...
Kekuatan terakhirku ...
Of my strength...
Kerahkan semuanya ...
Wow. She took down a Killer Tiger in one blow.
Luar biasa.
Just who are you?
Kamu tuh apa-apaan?
There are beings of inexplicable power in this world known as ultimate species.
Di dunia ini ...
Dragonoids. Fairies. Demigods.
Ras naga. Ras spirit. Ras dewa.
They all count among the ultimate species.
Terdapat banyak ras terkuat.
But one of them is more rare than the rest.
Tapi ada satu ras yang cukup langka.
And that is...
Itu adalah ...
A Cat Spirit?
... Spirit Kucing?
And... I... am... done.
Aku ... sudah ... nggak kuat.
Hey!
H-Hei!
Hey, are you all right? Were you hurt?
Hei, kamu tak apa? Kamu terluka?
Say something!
Bertahanlah!
So...
La ...
So?
La?
So hungry...
Lapar banget, nih ...
She's... the real deal?
Dia ... asli, 'kan?
Despite being one of the ultimate species,
Bahkan di antara ras terkuat ...
the Cat Spirits are said to be on the verge of extinction.
... Spirit Kucing disebut hampir punah.
They can't use magic, but they've evolved to have athletic abilities
Meski tak bisa sihir ...
that make them among the ultimate in the world.
Membuatnya terkuat di dunia.
And she really is one?
Dia asli, 'kan?
Thank you so much! You're a life-saver.
Terima kasih! Aku tertolong, nih.
I thought I was gonna die back there.
Kukira aku bakal mati.
I'm just glad I had some traveling rations on me.
Untung saja aku bawa makanan.
Still, are you sure you're not exaggerating?
Tapi itu berlebihan, 'kan?
Not at all!
Enggak, kok!
I've gone days without anything to eat or drink.
Aku belum makan dan minum berhari-hari.
I could see my grandparents in heaven waving me over.
Aku melihat kakek dan nenek di surga melambai.
She must've been in pretty rough shape.
Situasinya cukup buruk, ya.
That would've been another step toward extinction.
Selangkah menuju kepunahan, tuh.
Okay, extremely bad shape!
Ternyata sangat buruk!
Oh, I never introduced myself, did I?
Oh, aku belum mengenalkan diri, ya?
My name's Kanade! As you can see, I'm a Cat Spirit.
Aku Kanade!
Nice to meet you!
Salam kenal, ya!
I'm Rein Shroud.
Aku Rein Shroud.
I ran into you in the middle of my adventurer's trial, miss.
Aku bertemu kamu saat tes petualang.
Wh-What is it?
A-Apa?
I'd rather you call me "Kanade" than "miss."
Bukan "kamu," tapi panggil "Kanade."
Okay, if you call me Rein.
Oke, panggil saja aku Rein.
Okay then, Rein!
Ya, Rein!
I'm glad you're the one who helped me!
Aku senang Rein yang menolongku!
What were you doing out here in the first place, Kanade?
Kenapa Kanade terkapar di sini?
I mean, it's kind of strange to find an endangered Cat Spirit
Yah, di hutan biasa-biasa ini ...
I've just been traveling, is all.
Aku cuma berkelana.
There's not many of us, so we live quietly, deep in the mountains...
Jumlah kami tak banyak, jadi kami tinggal di gunung.
But life was kind of boring that way,
Tapi membosankan hidup begitu.
so I went on a journey, where I ran into you,
Jadi aku berkelana dan bertemu Rein ...
who saved me!
... dan ditolong!
Feels kind of like fate!
Ini seperti takdir, ya!
Now, tell me about you, Rein!
Oke, ceritakan tentangmu, Rein!
Then you were in the Hero's party, Rein?
Kamu anggota party pahlawan, Rein?
Yeah. Only for six months, though.
Ya. Cuma 6 bulan, sih.
This is strange...
Aneh, nih ...
Thinking about it has been so depressing, I never told anyone else,
Aku tak mau memikirkannya atau memberitahu orang lain ...
but I'm telling Kanade everything.
... tapi malah kuceritakan pada Kanade.
And that's how it went...
Begitulah ...
Kanade?
Kanade?
That Hero ought to be ashamed!
Pahlawan itu tak bisa dimaafkan!
I can't believe he kicked you out...
Malah mengusir Rein ...
When you're such a nice person!
Padahal Rein sangat baik!
Are you mad on my behalf?
Kamu marah untukku?
Of course I am!
Tentu saja!
Because Rein, you're... I...
Habisnya Rein, aku ...
You're really sweet, Kanade. But it's okay now.
Kamu baik, Kanade.
They were right about me being a hindrance,
Memang benar aku beban ...
and I doubt any good would have come from staying in that party.
... dan tak ada baiknya aku tetap di party itu.
Okay.
Gitu, ya.
If you're not mad, Rein, then I'm not mad.
Jika Rein tak peduli, aku juga tak peduli.
Still kinda frustrated though...
Meski agak kesal, sih ...
Yeah.
Ya.
Thank you, though.
Terima kasih, ya.
Oh, no! That was on reflex...
Gawat! Refleks ...
What a relief. She doesn't seem to mind.
Syukurlah. Dia tak membencinya.
But I want to make one thing clear.
Tapi biar kuperjelas satu hal.
You're not useless at all, Rein!
Kamu bukan orang yang tak berguna, Rein!
If anything, you're really strong!
Malahan, kamu sangat kuat!
But I'm just a Beast Tamer.
Aku cuma Beast Tamer, lo.
And you've got an incredible gift for it!
Bakatmu itu sangat luar biasa!
The reason being...
Habisnya ...
I'm pretty sure you could tame me, Rein.
Rein mungkin bisa menjinakkanku.
How do I put this?
Gimana bilangnya, ya?
It's like the second I saw you, I felt this buzzing, like electricity!
Saat melihat Rein, aku merasa kayak kesetrum!
I thought that you would be able to tame me.
Aku merasa orang ini ... Rein bisa menjinakkanku.
There are only a handful of people in the whole world who can tame Cat Spirits!
Orang yang bisa menjinakkan Spirit Kucing ...
Which means you're really amazing, Rein!
Jadi Rein tuh hebat!
Me, taming a Cat Spirit?
Aku menjinakkan Spirit Kucing?
I never even considered it before...
Aku tak pernah memikirkannya ...
Come on, Rein!
Hei, Rein!
Try taming me!
Mau coba menjinakkanku?
If I could actually tame an ultimate species...
Jika bisa menjinakkan ras terkuat ...
It would be an unimaginably big help.
... itu pasti sangat melegakan.
Nothing like that would ever happen again.
Aku tak mau hal itu terjadi lagi.
With an ultimate species...
Jika ada ras terkuat ...
Feels kind of like fate!
Ini seperti takdir, ya!
Oh... that's right.
Ya ... benar.
It's not because she's from an ultimate species.
Bukan karena dia ras terkuat.
I want to get to know Kanade better.
Aku ingin lebih mengenal Kanade.
Okay. Let's try it.
Oke, akan kucoba.
Yeah!
Ya!
My name is Rein Shroud.
Namaku Rein Shroud.
In establishing this new contract, a bond is formed.
Menjalin kontrak baru, membentuk ikatan.
An oath in our hearts, hopes in our souls...
Sumpah di hati, harapan di jiwa ...
Your power, in my hand.
Kekuatan di tangan ini.
Speak now your name.
Sebutkan namamu.
If Kanade gives her name now, the contract will be formed.
Jika Kanade menyebutkan namanya ...
Otherwise...
Jika tidak ...
Kanade.
Kanade.
Did it work?
Sudah selesai?
Yep. The contract is sealed.
Ya. Kontrak terbentuk.
Look at the palm of your hand.
Lihatlah telapak tanganmu.
There's some kind of weird pattern!
Ada pola aneh, nih!
It's the symbol of what links us.
Itu simbol yang menghubungkan kita.
You and I are contracted now, Kanade.
Kita sekarang punya kontrak, Kanade.
Really? Then this means you and I are bound together, huh!
Gitu, ya?
That's great!
Senangnya!
Bound together?
Ikatan?
Was I wrong?
Eh, salah, ya?
No, you're right.
Tidak. Benar, kok.
It symbolizes our bond, Kanade!
Itu bukti ikatan kita, Kanade!
Yeah!
Ya!
It's a pleasure to be traveling with you, Rein!
Mohon bantuannya, Rein!
The feeling is mutual!
Sama-sama, ya!
Wha—hey!
Wah! Hei!
There are the ultimate species, with inexplicable power...
Ada ras terkuat dengan kekuatan nonstandar.
I was a Beast Tamer kicked out of the Hero's party,
Aku Beast Tamer yang diusir dari party petualang ...
bereft of a goal or any comrades...
... tanpa teman dan tujuan.
And now one of the ultimate species is working with me.
Dan sekarang ...
Hey, aren't we going back to town?
Hei, nggak balik ke kota?
I need to finish my adventurer's trial first.
Aku harus selesaikan tesku dulu.
I think they should be around here somewhere....
Uh, harusnya di sekitar sini ...
Ah, there we go.
Oh, itu dia.
Rabbits?
Kelinci?
Yep. First, a temporary contract...
Ya, kontrak sementara dulu ...
There he goes.
Dia pergi.
But, wait, Rein how can you—
Eh, tunggu, Rein, kok bisa kontrak—
Next, he brings his friends over.
Dia akan kumpulkan temannya.
Friends?!
Temannya?!
I'm in fluffy heaven!
Surga kelembutan, nih!
Then I form temporary contracts with all of them.
Lalu kontrak sementara dengan mereka semua.
Okay, everyone,
Dengar, semuanya ...
I need you to look for medicinal herbs in the area and bring them to me.
... cari herba di sini dan bawa padaku.
Be careful not to mistake them for food and eat them!
Jangan salah mengira itu makanan, ya!
Okay, off you go.
Oke, pergilah.
That ought to do it...
Yah, begitulah ...
What's wrong?
Ada apa?
What the heck is going on?!
Apa-apaan ini?!
You were able to tame so many at once! And give them complex commands!
Bisa menjinakkan banyak dan memberi perintah rumit ...
Is that really so rare?
Memangnya itu mengejutkan?
You bet it is!
Tentu saja!
Normal
Normal
Even with temporary contracts, most Beast Tamers can only handle one at a time!
Kontrak sementara tuh ...
Weird
Aneh
Not to mention, you've tamed me,
Rein sudah menjinakkanku ...
so you shouldn't be able to do any more, Rein!
... jadi harusnya nggak bisa nambah!
I mean, I know I said you were an amazing Beast Tamer, but...
Yah, aku memang bilang Rein tuh Beast Tamer hebat ...
This is supposed to be impossible!
Tapi ini mustahil!
Huh, you know a lot about this stuff, Kanade.
Eh, kamu tahu banyak, Kanade.
How is this happening?!
Kok bisa?!
I've never heard of a Beast Tamer doing all this at once!
Aku tak tahu ada Beast Tamer yang bisa gini!
I'm not sure what to tell you...
Meski kamu bilang gitu ...
Back home, everyone can do this sort of thing.
Di kampungku, semua orang bisa.
It's just normal for a Beast Tamer, isn't it?
Ini normal untuk Beast Tamer, 'kan?
It's not even kind of normal!
Ini sama sekali nggak normal!
And you called me inexplicable?!
Siapa yang nonstandar, nih?!
(Comrades)
Rekan
Next time: "Comrades."
Selanjutnya: "Rekan."